# Jacob Washington

Software Developer

Address Corona, CA, 92882

**Phone** (714) 824-0381

**E-mail** jacobwashington.dev@gmail.com

LinkedIn www.linkedin.com/in/jacob-

washington

**WWW** jdotdev.com

I'm a Full Stack Software Developer who loves designing and building beautiful, precise applications, from front to back. A veteran of the armed forces, my unique background and experience define who I am as a developer. I value clear and open communication, strive for excellence with every application I build, and challenge myself to leave all things better than I found them. As a team member, I endeavor to bring clarity to our mission and goals, and coherency among my peers. I do not hesitate to lift others as I pull. I'm quietly confident, naturally curious, and perpetually working to improve myself as a developer, one application at a time.

#### **Skills**



Database Architecture	Good
User Experience	Good
Full Stack Software Development	Excellent

# **Work History**

## 2018-04 - 2018-10 Security Host

Disney Parks, Experiences And Products, Anaheim, CA

- Leveraged modern security technologies, critical-thinking, and interpersonal communication skills to identify and deter security threats at one of the nation's highest valued terrorism targets
- Maintained professionalism and coherency, under increased pressure, in a dynamic and always changing environment
- Adapted quickly in order to deliver elegant, effective solutions to security dilemmas

# 2017-05 - 2017-12 Security Professional

Star Protection Agency LLC, Seattle, WA

- Developed security procedures for commercial office locations, leveraging research, analytical thinking, and interpersonal skills to deliver security solutions tailored to the individual client
- With careful attention to detail, and emphasis on the desired outcome, adapted quickly in volatile environments to secure at risk individuals and impede malicious activities

# 2015-06 - 2017-04 Ramp Agent

Southwest Airlines, Seattle, WA

- Led teams of up to 5 individuals, managing loading and unloading operations for commercial aircrafts and ensuring that aircraft and their passengers were moved safely to and from boarding locations
- Maintained accountability of, and provided safe transportation for, upwards of \$1M in personal luggage and commercial cargo per shift

# 2011-07 - 2014-11 Combat Engineer

US Army, Joint Base Lewis-McChord, WA

- Led and mentored new recruits as they entered the 14th Engineer Battalion
- Devised a training plan and constructed training resources for soldiers using mine detection equipment in support of Operation Enduring

Freedom

 Served as an integral member of a team, successfully conducting over 3000 hours of combat operations in support of Operation Enduring Freedom

#### **Education**

## 2021-08 - Current No Degree: Computer Science

Santiago Canyon College - Orange, CA

#### 2020-12 - 2021-04 Certificate of Training: Software Development

General Assembly - San Francisco, CA

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

# 2016-06 - 2018-11 No Degree: Sociology And Anthropology

Seattle Central College - Seattle, WA

As a student of sociology at Seattle Central College, I took my learning from pages to practice. Theories and concepts I'd discovered—both in the classroom and in my own studies—greatly assisted my development as a leader in the BSU and my ability to lead the BSU in coalescing with organizations with similar goals.